<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-16T19:25:05+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Grounds of the City</title><subtitle>A student's journey with coffee</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Onward &amp;amp; Upward</title><link href="/onward_and_upward" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Onward &amp; Upward" /><published>2020-04-01T11:59:59+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-01T11:59:59+00:00</updated><id>/onward_and_upward</id><content type="html" xml:base="/onward_and_upward">&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I have been putting this off for a while now. It has almost been a month since I have last posted on this blog. When I look back at the content I created before, I give a wry smile towards my oblivity (yes I made this word up because it sounds cooler than obliviousness) at the greater situation at large. COVID-19 has undoubtedly affected us all but, while it may seem terrible at first, I have faith that COVID-19 will spark great change in society that is beneficial to all of us.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Personally, I now look back at all the things I have taken for granted with newfound appreciation. This once-in-a-century disease that is rampaging across the world has made me really assess the little things in life. Anywhere from making coffee for my friends to walking into a new coffee shop, I truly miss the little things about this hobby of mine. Of course, I am grateful for so much more that is unrelated to coffee, but then again this is a blog about coffee.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I really hope that the people I have met throughout my coffee adventure are doing well. I know that these times are hard for everyone, but especially small businesses, so wishing them all the best. It truly is the people that you meet in your journey who define your story. There have been wonderful baristas and random people that I have met at coffee shops that defined my love for coffee. And it’s sadly poetic how only in times like these do we stop to think about how important those people are in our development.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In an age of social distancing, I will no longer have the luxury of walking into a new coffee shop and posit opinions of taste. Instead, I want to talk about the under-the-rug, nerdy stuff that really gets my blood pumping when it comes to coffee. Anywhere from ‘how to make coffee’, ‘how can I start making great coffee’, or ‘why do we even use water as our solute’ are all questions I want to talk about and hopefully spark interest in someone else to begin their own coffee addiction.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Pan</name></author><category term="tea" /><summary type="html">Honestly, I have been putting this off for a while now. It has almost been a month since I have last posted on this blog. When I look back at the content I created before, I give a wry smile towards my oblivity (yes I made this word up because it sounds cooler than obliviousness) at the greater situation at large. COVID-19 has undoubtedly affected us all but, while it may seem terrible at first, I have faith that COVID-19 will spark great change in society that is beneficial to all of us. Personally, I now look back at all the things I have taken for granted with newfound appreciation. This once-in-a-century disease that is rampaging across the world has made me really assess the little things in life. Anywhere from making coffee for my friends to walking into a new coffee shop, I truly miss the little things about this hobby of mine. Of course, I am grateful for so much more that is unrelated to coffee, but then again this is a blog about coffee. I really hope that the people I have met throughout my coffee adventure are doing well. I know that these times are hard for everyone, but especially small businesses, so wishing them all the best. It truly is the people that you meet in your journey who define your story. There have been wonderful baristas and random people that I have met at coffee shops that defined my love for coffee. And it’s sadly poetic how only in times like these do we stop to think about how important those people are in our development. In an age of social distancing, I will no longer have the luxury of walking into a new coffee shop and posit opinions of taste. Instead, I want to talk about the under-the-rug, nerdy stuff that really gets my blood pumping when it comes to coffee. Anywhere from ‘how to make coffee’, ‘how can I start making great coffee’, or ‘why do we even use water as our solute’ are all questions I want to talk about and hopefully spark interest in someone else to begin their own coffee addiction.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Liquid Thought</title><link href="/liquid-thought" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Liquid Thought" /><published>2020-03-08T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-08T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/liquid-thought</id><content type="html" xml:base="/liquid-thought">&lt;p&gt;The sun is rising right now. The sky is a full light blue with rays of light peeking through tall trees and buildings. I’m sipping my coffee. It’s a little over-extracted, but that’s okay. It’s way too early to be writing about coffee. To be completely transparent, I didn’t go to a coffee shop this week. It’s not because I didn’t have the time, I just didn’t feel like going to one. For this post, I want to expose my mind and pour my thoughts onto writing. I want my liquid thoughts to solidify in prose. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have no idea why I didn’t feel like going to a coffee shop this week. It’s not that I didn’t have time and I certainly didn’t run out of places to go. Maybe like an over-extracted coffee, I just exposed myself too much, too quickly, for far too long. To clarify, I’m not sick of coffee. I’m definitely far from it. Honestly, it’s kind of crazy to think that it’s been 10 weeks in the making for this little blog of mine. There have definitely been some posts that are far superior than others in my eyes, but &lt;strong&gt;The Grounds of the City&lt;/strong&gt; was always meant to simply be a breeding ground for my tender thoughts.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/gumption.jpg){:class=&quot;imglit&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Honestly, it baffles me that I’m doing this. I’m chuckling thinking about the absurdity of this blog and how far my passion for coffee has brought me. I originally came into &lt;strong&gt;The Grounds of the City&lt;/strong&gt; with no expecations on how it would look or any bearings on the type of content. I dived in thinking that I would simply “figure it out” as I went along. I honestly don’t know, and don’t care, if anyone reads these posts besides myself. This little blog of mine has essentially become a diary of anything from my absurd assumptions to snobbish takes on bean water. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As my 9th post, this very post marks 10 weeks since I started this project. I never really thought about where I wanted this to go. But looking back at where it all started, I’m quite happy to see how &lt;strong&gt;The Grounds of the City&lt;/strong&gt; has evolved over time. Of course, there is so much that I wish I could change about the blog (I mean let’s be honest, it looks like shit right now). I really hope to continue this hobby of mine beyond this quarter at school. Again, no expectations moving forward, and extremely excited to see where the future takes me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Pan</name></author><category term="tea" /><summary type="html">The sun is rising right now. The sky is a full light blue with rays of light peeking through tall trees and buildings. I’m sipping my coffee. It’s a little over-extracted, but that’s okay. It’s way too early to be writing about coffee. To be completely transparent, I didn’t go to a coffee shop this week. It’s not because I didn’t have the time, I just didn’t feel like going to one. For this post, I want to expose my mind and pour my thoughts onto writing. I want my liquid thoughts to solidify in prose. I have no idea why I didn’t feel like going to a coffee shop this week. It’s not that I didn’t have time and I certainly didn’t run out of places to go. Maybe like an over-extracted coffee, I just exposed myself too much, too quickly, for far too long. To clarify, I’m not sick of coffee. I’m definitely far from it. Honestly, it’s kind of crazy to think that it’s been 10 weeks in the making for this little blog of mine. There have definitely been some posts that are far superior than others in my eyes, but The Grounds of the City was always meant to simply be a breeding ground for my tender thoughts. Honestly, it baffles me that I’m doing this. I’m chuckling thinking about the absurdity of this blog and how far my passion for coffee has brought me. I originally came into The Grounds of the City with no expecations on how it would look or any bearings on the type of content. I dived in thinking that I would simply “figure it out” as I went along. I honestly don’t know, and don’t care, if anyone reads these posts besides myself. This little blog of mine has essentially become a diary of anything from my absurd assumptions to snobbish takes on bean water. As my 9th post, this very post marks 10 weeks since I started this project. I never really thought about where I wanted this to go. But looking back at where it all started, I’m quite happy to see how The Grounds of the City has evolved over time. Of course, there is so much that I wish I could change about the blog (I mean let’s be honest, it looks like shit right now). I really hope to continue this hobby of mine beyond this quarter at school. Again, no expectations moving forward, and extremely excited to see where the future takes me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Great</title><link href="/greatness" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Great" /><published>2020-03-01T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-01T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/greatness</id><content type="html" xml:base="/greatness">&lt;p&gt;What makes great coffee? This is a constantly evolving question that continues to alter itself as I puddle deeper into this vast space of bean water. It’s hard to rationalize passion. Sometimes, things just make sense and there is no logical explanation behind the emotions you feel. I find that true hobbies/passions are ones that challenge your self-image as you struggle to logically comprehend why your pursuing that passion. That sentence didn’t really make any sense whatsoever, but I guess that’s what I’m kind of getting at.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you came to me a year ago and asked me what constitutes great coffee. I would have given some shortsighted answer: complexity and balance. While this response is technically 100% accurate, it fails to recognize the nuances of a hobby that makes falling in love with it so easy. In many ways, coffee, like cars or watches, is a commodity and is holistically unnecessary in your life. Logically, it makes absolutely zero sense to be spending considerable sums of money on coffee, but billions of people around the globe do it every single day. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have said this before, but I want to reiterate this point. I don’t need coffee in my life. The caffeine doesn’t really impact my day-to-day in a way that makes me reliant on it. But I do love the act of making coffee and the bitter/sour/sweet taste of it. It’s very hard to explain what about the taste I like so much, but I guess I can break it down into what I like. Coffee, inherently, has a sour/sweet taste. This stems from the fact that coffee beans are actually not beans at all. They are pits of a cherry-like fruit. And when we roast these beans, the Maillard reactions impart a savory and bitter quality to these beans. Really great coffee has a unique character, such that you can never have the same exact cup twice. Ultimately, this is what I truly love about coffee. No matter how meticulous you try to make your coffee, it will always taste different and it will always be a new experience.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/verve-interior.jpg){:class=&quot;imglit&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This week, I went to a coffee shop called &lt;strong&gt;Verve Coffee Roasters&lt;/strong&gt;: they are a coffee roastery/cafe chain that is based in Santa Cruz. I actually have been drinking their Costa Rican Line for the past two weeks through my coffee subscription with &lt;a href=&quot;http://s.trdcfe.me/MtP3f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trade Coffee&lt;/a&gt;. It’s an amazing line of coffee beans with an almost tea-like quality: super clean, tastes like a fruit tea. Their cafes, however, are something else. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The one I went to was situated in Beverly Hills. One of the bougiest cafes I have ever stepped foot in, &lt;strong&gt;Verve Coffee Roasters&lt;/strong&gt; blew me away with their service and interior design. It truly fits the location it was placed in as the sunlight shone through the open space to complement a very Socal interior design. Best of all, their service was so extremely kind and warm. The coffee I got was a Kenyan pourover that came with a little card describing the notes within it. I also loved the fact that they gave me a tiny carafe as a little extra coffee.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/verve-pourover.jpg){:class=&quot;imglit&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The coffee itself was quite amazing. Full disclosure, &lt;strong&gt;Verve&lt;/strong&gt; charges each pourover differently as the cost of the beans is inherently disparate. Generally, this is a pretty good sign that a coffee shop knows what they are doing and that they understand the differences between good and great coffee. The Kenyan I had was 6 dollars and to be completely honest, I thought it was a fair price to pay. I know it sounds ridiculous to pay 6 dollars for a cup of coffee, but they honestly give you technically 1.5 cups of coffee because of the small carafe. Quality-wise, &lt;strong&gt;Verve&lt;/strong&gt; is a brand of coffee I personally like going to for my daily pourovers. I highly recommend coming to the shops to try out the beans they have in stock and then buying the ones you like online. I have found this to be a great way to understand and appreciate truly great coffee.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Pan</name></author><category term="places" /><summary type="html">What makes great coffee? This is a constantly evolving question that continues to alter itself as I puddle deeper into this vast space of bean water. It’s hard to rationalize passion. Sometimes, things just make sense and there is no logical explanation behind the emotions you feel. I find that true hobbies/passions are ones that challenge your self-image as you struggle to logically comprehend why your pursuing that passion. That sentence didn’t really make any sense whatsoever, but I guess that’s what I’m kind of getting at. If you came to me a year ago and asked me what constitutes great coffee. I would have given some shortsighted answer: complexity and balance. While this response is technically 100% accurate, it fails to recognize the nuances of a hobby that makes falling in love with it so easy. In many ways, coffee, like cars or watches, is a commodity and is holistically unnecessary in your life. Logically, it makes absolutely zero sense to be spending considerable sums of money on coffee, but billions of people around the globe do it every single day. I have said this before, but I want to reiterate this point. I don’t need coffee in my life. The caffeine doesn’t really impact my day-to-day in a way that makes me reliant on it. But I do love the act of making coffee and the bitter/sour/sweet taste of it. It’s very hard to explain what about the taste I like so much, but I guess I can break it down into what I like. Coffee, inherently, has a sour/sweet taste. This stems from the fact that coffee beans are actually not beans at all. They are pits of a cherry-like fruit. And when we roast these beans, the Maillard reactions impart a savory and bitter quality to these beans. Really great coffee has a unique character, such that you can never have the same exact cup twice. Ultimately, this is what I truly love about coffee. No matter how meticulous you try to make your coffee, it will always taste different and it will always be a new experience. This week, I went to a coffee shop called Verve Coffee Roasters: they are a coffee roastery/cafe chain that is based in Santa Cruz. I actually have been drinking their Costa Rican Line for the past two weeks through my coffee subscription with Trade Coffee. It’s an amazing line of coffee beans with an almost tea-like quality: super clean, tastes like a fruit tea. Their cafes, however, are something else. The one I went to was situated in Beverly Hills. One of the bougiest cafes I have ever stepped foot in, Verve Coffee Roasters blew me away with their service and interior design. It truly fits the location it was placed in as the sunlight shone through the open space to complement a very Socal interior design. Best of all, their service was so extremely kind and warm. The coffee I got was a Kenyan pourover that came with a little card describing the notes within it. I also loved the fact that they gave me a tiny carafe as a little extra coffee. The coffee itself was quite amazing. Full disclosure, Verve charges each pourover differently as the cost of the beans is inherently disparate. Generally, this is a pretty good sign that a coffee shop knows what they are doing and that they understand the differences between good and great coffee. The Kenyan I had was 6 dollars and to be completely honest, I thought it was a fair price to pay. I know it sounds ridiculous to pay 6 dollars for a cup of coffee, but they honestly give you technically 1.5 cups of coffee because of the small carafe. Quality-wise, Verve is a brand of coffee I personally like going to for my daily pourovers. I highly recommend coming to the shops to try out the beans they have in stock and then buying the ones you like online. I have found this to be a great way to understand and appreciate truly great coffee.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Comfortability</title><link href="/comfortability" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comfortability" /><published>2020-02-23T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-23T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/comfortability</id><content type="html" xml:base="/comfortability">&lt;p&gt;Comfortability. Why is it that so many of us want to live a life of spontaneity but implicitly strive to avoid discomfort? Personally, I fear apathy, but I don’t actively pursue discomfort. It’s easy to say that we like spontaneity, but when it comes to putting action to our words it honestly is so hard. Even in my pursuit of coffee, I find myself defaulting to things that I like rather than actively exploring the vast diversity the coffee world has to offer. For some reason, I find my actions, more often than not, fail to completely reflect my desires, and that bothers me.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I like pourovers, specifically Ethiopian single origins that are light-medium roasted. When I go to a coffee shop, the two questions I ask first are 1) “Do you do pourovers?” and 2) “Do you carry Ethiopian beans?”. If they have them, great, color me happy. If not, I settle for whatever beans they have or a cappuccino. While I don’t regret having a preference for pourovers over espresso drinks, I do wish I actively tried to truly experience and understand great espresso. After all, how can I be a coffee snob without understanding espresso?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In my attempt to stretch my boundaries and try new things, I recently went to a place called &lt;strong&gt;Millcross Coffee Bar &amp;amp; Kitchen&lt;/strong&gt;. Newly opened, &lt;strong&gt;Millcross&lt;/strong&gt; seemed to be the perfect place for me to start my journey towards discomfort in the world of coffee. I ordered a macchiato. To those who don’t know, a macchiato is an espresso drink that is somewhat of a middle ground between a cappuccino and an espresso shot. In Italian, macchiato roughly translates to “stained” or “spotted”. Unlike the macchiatos Starbucks and most cafes offer, true macchiato is simply a shot of espresso and a dash of steamed milk.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/millcross-macchiato.jpg){:class=&quot;imglit&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve had macchiato before, but never done extremely well. Most are either too sweet (too much milk) or too bitter (basically espresso). The macchiato I had at &lt;strong&gt;Millcross&lt;/strong&gt;, on the other hand, was amazing. Not only did it taste amazing, but it looked absolutely beautiful. One of my favorite aspects of espresso drinks is latte art. Macchiatos inherently use little milk and are smaller than lattes, so the fact that they were able to do something like this is actually insane. For someone who is used to staring at the dark abyss of black coffee, I find the expressionistic quality of espresso drinks fascinating and refreshing. Wow, it truly is these small moments that I realize how much I love coffee. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I want to end by expanding on the notion of taste. When I tell someone that a coffee taste amazing, most people just look at me like an animal at the zoo. Taste is something that is highly subjective, but I want to share my opinion and thoughts on tasting coffee. Personally, I generally enjoy coffee that are complex and bright. Now what exactly does this mean? If you think about your typical diner coffee, you probably think of an inoffensive, bold, coffee that is piping hot. It’s not particularly special or flavorful, it just tastes like plain old coffee. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Complexity simply means that the coffee flavor evolves over time and tastes more than just plain coffee. How is this possible? Chemical compounds. I plan to go over the whole process of taste in a later post, but simply put, coffee from different places of the world produces a different flavor profile. Some are more acidic than others and others are more bitter. A bright coffee is more acidic because that acidity is born from compounds that are inherently citrusy in flavor. Most Ethiopians produce a bright taste and I personally find that this acidity perfectly complements the bitterness of the coffee. Next time you get a coffee, let it sit in your mouth just a tad longer and try to think about what you are tasting. You might surprise yourself and find that the flavor of the coffee changes or becomes more transparent!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Pan</name></author><category term="places" /><summary type="html">Comfortability. Why is it that so many of us want to live a life of spontaneity but implicitly strive to avoid discomfort? Personally, I fear apathy, but I don’t actively pursue discomfort. It’s easy to say that we like spontaneity, but when it comes to putting action to our words it honestly is so hard. Even in my pursuit of coffee, I find myself defaulting to things that I like rather than actively exploring the vast diversity the coffee world has to offer. For some reason, I find my actions, more often than not, fail to completely reflect my desires, and that bothers me. I like pourovers, specifically Ethiopian single origins that are light-medium roasted. When I go to a coffee shop, the two questions I ask first are 1) “Do you do pourovers?” and 2) “Do you carry Ethiopian beans?”. If they have them, great, color me happy. If not, I settle for whatever beans they have or a cappuccino. While I don’t regret having a preference for pourovers over espresso drinks, I do wish I actively tried to truly experience and understand great espresso. After all, how can I be a coffee snob without understanding espresso? In my attempt to stretch my boundaries and try new things, I recently went to a place called Millcross Coffee Bar &amp;amp; Kitchen. Newly opened, Millcross seemed to be the perfect place for me to start my journey towards discomfort in the world of coffee. I ordered a macchiato. To those who don’t know, a macchiato is an espresso drink that is somewhat of a middle ground between a cappuccino and an espresso shot. In Italian, macchiato roughly translates to “stained” or “spotted”. Unlike the macchiatos Starbucks and most cafes offer, true macchiato is simply a shot of espresso and a dash of steamed milk. I’ve had macchiato before, but never done extremely well. Most are either too sweet (too much milk) or too bitter (basically espresso). The macchiato I had at Millcross, on the other hand, was amazing. Not only did it taste amazing, but it looked absolutely beautiful. One of my favorite aspects of espresso drinks is latte art. Macchiatos inherently use little milk and are smaller than lattes, so the fact that they were able to do something like this is actually insane. For someone who is used to staring at the dark abyss of black coffee, I find the expressionistic quality of espresso drinks fascinating and refreshing. Wow, it truly is these small moments that I realize how much I love coffee. I want to end by expanding on the notion of taste. When I tell someone that a coffee taste amazing, most people just look at me like an animal at the zoo. Taste is something that is highly subjective, but I want to share my opinion and thoughts on tasting coffee. Personally, I generally enjoy coffee that are complex and bright. Now what exactly does this mean? If you think about your typical diner coffee, you probably think of an inoffensive, bold, coffee that is piping hot. It’s not particularly special or flavorful, it just tastes like plain old coffee. Complexity simply means that the coffee flavor evolves over time and tastes more than just plain coffee. How is this possible? Chemical compounds. I plan to go over the whole process of taste in a later post, but simply put, coffee from different places of the world produces a different flavor profile. Some are more acidic than others and others are more bitter. A bright coffee is more acidic because that acidity is born from compounds that are inherently citrusy in flavor. Most Ethiopians produce a bright taste and I personally find that this acidity perfectly complements the bitterness of the coffee. Next time you get a coffee, let it sit in your mouth just a tad longer and try to think about what you are tasting. You might surprise yourself and find that the flavor of the coffee changes or becomes more transparent!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Genesis</title><link href="/genesis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Genesis" /><published>2020-02-16T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-16T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/genesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="/genesis">&lt;p&gt;Last week, I talked about the genesis of my coffee addiction. It honestly still amazes me how the “land down under” managed to perfect their coffee. In many ways, Australia’s coffee culture shows the true cultural power of globalization and immigration. See during World War II, the Italian and Greek families fled from their home and immigrated to countries like Australia. With their families, these immigrants brought their traditions and values but, most importantly, they brought their stovetop coffee makers. Thanks, Hitler.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
While all the rest of the world was buried by the convenience-driven coffee culture of the First and Second Wave movement, Australia was fearlessly experimenting with traditional Italian espresso-making by bastardizing it with milk. Despite its Italian roots, Australian coffee was more experimental and explorative as the mixing of cultures sparked new ideas. It’s kind of cheesy to say this but, at the end of the day, Australian coffee is just better because the people care more. The emphasis of quality over convenience is a core tenet of their coffee culture that isn’t truly reflected in other cultures. Once again, thanks, Hitler. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In all seriousness, I find it truly amazing the power immigration has on culture. It’s honestly so amazing to see countries opening their doors to immigrants because the benefits are so incredibly powerful. The melding of cultures breeds innovation both culturally and intellectually. In the world of coffee, you can thank Australia for popularizing anything from macchiatos to flat whites. In many ways, I find the best qualities of the world are at the intersection between different ideologies; coffee is no different.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/ministry-of-coffee-front.jpg){:class=&quot;img&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Next to my school is an Australian cafe called &lt;strong&gt;Ministry of Coffee&lt;/strong&gt;. Nostalgic of the coffee from down under, I went to &lt;strong&gt;Ministry of Coffee&lt;/strong&gt; because I wanted some semblance of obsessive coffee culture. In terms of quality of coffee, it’s honestly just okay. All of their coffee is roasted in Sydney and they only have one blend. For an Australian cafe, I find it hard to believe that they don’t carry any single origins or other blends. They also don’t do pourovers which is my personal go-to order (sad face). That being said, I think they are the only coffee shop that I have been to in Los Angeles that knows how to make a long black. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In terms of pricing for the quality of coffee, &lt;strong&gt;Ministry of Coffee&lt;/strong&gt; isn’t a steal in my opinion. Compared to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://groundsofthecity.com/location/2020/02/02/sustainability.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Coffee Connection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Ministry of Coffee’s&lt;/strong&gt; drinks are more expensive for little to no additional value. The long black I ordered was 4 dollars and it was a little watery for my taste. But of course, this is all personal preference and I’m an absolute coffee fiend. I will say though, the smell of &lt;strong&gt;Ministry of Coffee&lt;/strong&gt; distinctly reminded me of Australian cafes with a mix of Aussie pastries and espresso. I haven’t tried any of their milk-based espresso drinks, but I have hope that they will be much better.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To be completely transparent, I’m not the biggest expert on espresso. Currently, I’m really deep into pourover coffee and I haven’t really developed any sophistication on great espresso; so definitely take my opinion with a grain of salt. Espresso is something I want to get into but it’s so hard to experiment without a machine. If anyone wants to fuel my coffee addiction and buy me an espresso machine I will immortalize you. But until then, I think I’ll stick to what I know best: pourover.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Pan</name></author><category term="places" /><summary type="html">Last week, I talked about the genesis of my coffee addiction. It honestly still amazes me how the “land down under” managed to perfect their coffee. In many ways, Australia’s coffee culture shows the true cultural power of globalization and immigration. See during World War II, the Italian and Greek families fled from their home and immigrated to countries like Australia. With their families, these immigrants brought their traditions and values but, most importantly, they brought their stovetop coffee makers. Thanks, Hitler. While all the rest of the world was buried by the convenience-driven coffee culture of the First and Second Wave movement, Australia was fearlessly experimenting with traditional Italian espresso-making by bastardizing it with milk. Despite its Italian roots, Australian coffee was more experimental and explorative as the mixing of cultures sparked new ideas. It’s kind of cheesy to say this but, at the end of the day, Australian coffee is just better because the people care more. The emphasis of quality over convenience is a core tenet of their coffee culture that isn’t truly reflected in other cultures. Once again, thanks, Hitler. In all seriousness, I find it truly amazing the power immigration has on culture. It’s honestly so amazing to see countries opening their doors to immigrants because the benefits are so incredibly powerful. The melding of cultures breeds innovation both culturally and intellectually. In the world of coffee, you can thank Australia for popularizing anything from macchiatos to flat whites. In many ways, I find the best qualities of the world are at the intersection between different ideologies; coffee is no different. Next to my school is an Australian cafe called Ministry of Coffee. Nostalgic of the coffee from down under, I went to Ministry of Coffee because I wanted some semblance of obsessive coffee culture. In terms of quality of coffee, it’s honestly just okay. All of their coffee is roasted in Sydney and they only have one blend. For an Australian cafe, I find it hard to believe that they don’t carry any single origins or other blends. They also don’t do pourovers which is my personal go-to order (sad face). That being said, I think they are the only coffee shop that I have been to in Los Angeles that knows how to make a long black. In terms of pricing for the quality of coffee, Ministry of Coffee isn’t a steal in my opinion. Compared to Coffee Connection, Ministry of Coffee’s drinks are more expensive for little to no additional value. The long black I ordered was 4 dollars and it was a little watery for my taste. But of course, this is all personal preference and I’m an absolute coffee fiend. I will say though, the smell of Ministry of Coffee distinctly reminded me of Australian cafes with a mix of Aussie pastries and espresso. I haven’t tried any of their milk-based espresso drinks, but I have hope that they will be much better. To be completely transparent, I’m not the biggest expert on espresso. Currently, I’m really deep into pourover coffee and I haven’t really developed any sophistication on great espresso; so definitely take my opinion with a grain of salt. Espresso is something I want to get into but it’s so hard to experiment without a machine. If anyone wants to fuel my coffee addiction and buy me an espresso machine I will immortalize you. But until then, I think I’ll stick to what I know best: pourover.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nostalgia</title><link href="/nostalgia" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nostalgia" /><published>2020-02-09T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-09T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/nostalgia</id><content type="html" xml:base="/nostalgia">&lt;p&gt;The other day, I was at a coffee shop trying an &lt;em&gt;Ethiopian Single Origin pourover&lt;/em&gt;. Looking back on that cumbersome phrase, I realize how snobbish coffee can sound. Let’s break down that order real quick. &lt;em&gt;Pourover&lt;/em&gt; is a technique that uses percolation (dripping) to extract soluble compounds from ground coffee. &lt;em&gt;Single Origin&lt;/em&gt; means all the beans are sourced from one origin; this, however, doesn’t mean they are all from the same farm. &lt;em&gt;Ethiopian&lt;/em&gt; describes the place of origin, this only applies to single origin coffee. Now, let’s move on.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You might have heard the phrase &lt;em&gt;Single Origin&lt;/em&gt; before and may have wondered, what’s the big deal? We can separate coffee into two groups: Single Origins and Blends. Single Origin coffee has been at the crux of the rise in specialty coffee. They are unique and exotic by nature as all the beans are sourced from the same region, making a region-unique brew. But because of its singularity, Single Origin coffee has a high propensity for inconsistency. For coffee enthusiasts, Single Origins tend to be the clear cut winner as it provides a diverse and fun way to go about trying the coffee of the world. Personally, I prefer the bright, fruity flavors of a &lt;em&gt;naturally processed Ethiopian&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Columbian&lt;/em&gt;. It’s bold, it’s exotic, it’s amazing.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Coffee purists might tell you that all blends are terrible. Well, that’s wrong. Blends, as the name suggests, are a combination of different coffee bean crops. Back in the day, the first blends were Mocha-Java blends (Mocha from Yemen and Java from Indonesia). But nowadays, we could have blends from all around the world and the understanding of how to make really good blends has changed in the past decade. Done well, great Blends produce a consistent, well-rounded, and unique flavor. With no harsh notes jutting out, Blends provide for an approachable tasting experience that is more suitable for espressos. If you are new to brewing coffee or want a well-rounded coffee that can last you months, then a blend might be the avenue of choice.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/single_origin_interior.jpg){:class=&quot;img&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Over the past summer, I went to Australia with my mom. Before going there, I had a mild interest in coffee with the extent of my knowledge limited to the core basics and taste. Australia changed all of that. If you don’t know, the coffee culture in Australia is insane. Coffee for them is a way of life and must be done at a high standard. For someone crazy obsessive like me, this was doing like crack.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Out of all the cafes I went to at my time in Australia, &lt;strong&gt;Single O&lt;/strong&gt; was, by far, my favorite spot in the Central Business District. There is just something about walking up to a coffee bar amidst a bustling city that just speaks to me. The coffee was divine, obviously, and their staff were so friendly. They truly opened my eyes to the world of great coffee and my obsession with Single Origin coffee. Fun fact: &lt;strong&gt;Single O&lt;/strong&gt; is credited for popularizing the concept of Single Origin coffee in Sydney.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/single-origin-coffee.png) --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I guess, in some ways, I cheated a little bit this week by talking about a cafe in Sydney, not Los Angeles. Feeling a wave of nostalgia, I couldn’t help but reminisce about the coffee I had 6 months ago. While I may not be able to recreate that specific taste ever in my life, the experience itself has turned me into a coffee fanatic. When I go to cafes nowadays, I always ask if they make a Single Origin pourover. It may sound snobbish, but my best conversations with baristas have always stemmed from that very question. Looking back at the genesis of this infatuation of mine, I can’t help but smile at where it all began, &lt;strong&gt;Single O&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Pan</name></author><category term="places" /><summary type="html">The other day, I was at a coffee shop trying an Ethiopian Single Origin pourover. Looking back on that cumbersome phrase, I realize how snobbish coffee can sound. Let’s break down that order real quick. Pourover is a technique that uses percolation (dripping) to extract soluble compounds from ground coffee. Single Origin means all the beans are sourced from one origin; this, however, doesn’t mean they are all from the same farm. Ethiopian describes the place of origin, this only applies to single origin coffee. Now, let’s move on. You might have heard the phrase Single Origin before and may have wondered, what’s the big deal? We can separate coffee into two groups: Single Origins and Blends. Single Origin coffee has been at the crux of the rise in specialty coffee. They are unique and exotic by nature as all the beans are sourced from the same region, making a region-unique brew. But because of its singularity, Single Origin coffee has a high propensity for inconsistency. For coffee enthusiasts, Single Origins tend to be the clear cut winner as it provides a diverse and fun way to go about trying the coffee of the world. Personally, I prefer the bright, fruity flavors of a naturally processed Ethiopian or Columbian. It’s bold, it’s exotic, it’s amazing. Coffee purists might tell you that all blends are terrible. Well, that’s wrong. Blends, as the name suggests, are a combination of different coffee bean crops. Back in the day, the first blends were Mocha-Java blends (Mocha from Yemen and Java from Indonesia). But nowadays, we could have blends from all around the world and the understanding of how to make really good blends has changed in the past decade. Done well, great Blends produce a consistent, well-rounded, and unique flavor. With no harsh notes jutting out, Blends provide for an approachable tasting experience that is more suitable for espressos. If you are new to brewing coffee or want a well-rounded coffee that can last you months, then a blend might be the avenue of choice. Over the past summer, I went to Australia with my mom. Before going there, I had a mild interest in coffee with the extent of my knowledge limited to the core basics and taste. Australia changed all of that. If you don’t know, the coffee culture in Australia is insane. Coffee for them is a way of life and must be done at a high standard. For someone crazy obsessive like me, this was doing like crack. Out of all the cafes I went to at my time in Australia, Single O was, by far, my favorite spot in the Central Business District. There is just something about walking up to a coffee bar amidst a bustling city that just speaks to me. The coffee was divine, obviously, and their staff were so friendly. They truly opened my eyes to the world of great coffee and my obsession with Single Origin coffee. Fun fact: Single O is credited for popularizing the concept of Single Origin coffee in Sydney. I guess, in some ways, I cheated a little bit this week by talking about a cafe in Sydney, not Los Angeles. Feeling a wave of nostalgia, I couldn’t help but reminisce about the coffee I had 6 months ago. While I may not be able to recreate that specific taste ever in my life, the experience itself has turned me into a coffee fanatic. When I go to cafes nowadays, I always ask if they make a Single Origin pourover. It may sound snobbish, but my best conversations with baristas have always stemmed from that very question. Looking back at the genesis of this infatuation of mine, I can’t help but smile at where it all began, Single O.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sustainability</title><link href="/sustainability" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sustainability" /><published>2020-02-02T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-02T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/sustainability</id><content type="html" xml:base="/sustainability">&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about sustainability. According to the National Coffee Association (NCA), 2.25 billion cups of coffee are consumed every single day. On top of k-cups and the 140 liters of water it takes to make a single cup of coffee, coffee consumption has a nontrivial impact on the environment. With growing interests towards promoting sustainable practices, cafes like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.groundsofthecity.com/opinions/2020/01/26/roots.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bar Nine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Coffee Connection&lt;/strong&gt; are taking off in the coffee-making business of doing things right.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As a non-profit cafe, &lt;strong&gt;Coffee Connection&lt;/strong&gt; was founded upon the notion of serving the greater community than a large corporation. They source their beans from &lt;a href=&quot;https://groundsforchange.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Grounds for Change&lt;/a&gt;, a Fair Trade and Carbon-Free roaster based in Seattle, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bicyclecoffeeco.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bicycle Coffee Roasters&lt;/a&gt;, a coffee roaster that only delivers by bike. Furthermore, &lt;strong&gt;Coffee Connection&lt;/strong&gt; proactively partners with the community by supporting local businesses and schools.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/coffee-connection-cappuccino.jpg){:class=&quot;img&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To be completely honest, the coffee isn’t amazing. Personally, I wouldn’t come to &lt;strong&gt;Coffee Connection&lt;/strong&gt; if I wanted to get blown away by an amazing cup of coffee. Since it is a non-profit cafe, their coffee is pretty affordable. I paid $3.50 for a cappuccino which ended up tasting pretty good considering the price I paid for it. However, the thing I loved most about &lt;strong&gt;Coffee Connection&lt;/strong&gt; was the space their provided.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/coffee-connection-interior.jpg){:class=&quot;img&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Coffee Connection&lt;/strong&gt; has an outdoor baroque courtyard dabbled with foliage and shade. If you are looking for a place to work during the day, I would highly recommend coming here. There is just something peaceful sitting in &lt;strong&gt;Coffee Connection&lt;/strong&gt; that gives off inspirational vibes. I will say that, at least for the day I went, it gets pretty crowded and seating for a large group can be diffcult. Having been established in 2000, &lt;strong&gt;Coffee Connection&lt;/strong&gt; has definitely found a community in Los Angeles focused on sustainability. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Personally, I would come to &lt;strong&gt;Coffee Connection&lt;/strong&gt; primarily for the space they provide and their mission. I believe in their mission towards promoting Fair Trade and Carbon-Free practices and I think they have developed a devoted community revolving around sustainability. In some ways, I would characterize them more as Second Wave coffee than Third Wave coffee. This is not to say that their coffee is terrible, Second Wave coffee just means an emphasis on the cafe itself rather than the specifics of coffee. To close, &lt;strong&gt;Coffee Connection&lt;/strong&gt; is a non-profit cafe that provides an inspiration space for people to chase their dreams starting with a sustainable cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Pan</name></author><category term="places" /><summary type="html">Let’s talk about sustainability. According to the National Coffee Association (NCA), 2.25 billion cups of coffee are consumed every single day. On top of k-cups and the 140 liters of water it takes to make a single cup of coffee, coffee consumption has a nontrivial impact on the environment. With growing interests towards promoting sustainable practices, cafes like Bar Nine and Coffee Connection are taking off in the coffee-making business of doing things right. As a non-profit cafe, Coffee Connection was founded upon the notion of serving the greater community than a large corporation. They source their beans from Grounds for Change, a Fair Trade and Carbon-Free roaster based in Seattle, and Bicycle Coffee Roasters, a coffee roaster that only delivers by bike. Furthermore, Coffee Connection proactively partners with the community by supporting local businesses and schools. To be completely honest, the coffee isn’t amazing. Personally, I wouldn’t come to Coffee Connection if I wanted to get blown away by an amazing cup of coffee. Since it is a non-profit cafe, their coffee is pretty affordable. I paid $3.50 for a cappuccino which ended up tasting pretty good considering the price I paid for it. However, the thing I loved most about Coffee Connection was the space their provided. Coffee Connection has an outdoor baroque courtyard dabbled with foliage and shade. If you are looking for a place to work during the day, I would highly recommend coming here. There is just something peaceful sitting in Coffee Connection that gives off inspirational vibes. I will say that, at least for the day I went, it gets pretty crowded and seating for a large group can be diffcult. Having been established in 2000, Coffee Connection has definitely found a community in Los Angeles focused on sustainability. Personally, I would come to Coffee Connection primarily for the space they provide and their mission. I believe in their mission towards promoting Fair Trade and Carbon-Free practices and I think they have developed a devoted community revolving around sustainability. In some ways, I would characterize them more as Second Wave coffee than Third Wave coffee. This is not to say that their coffee is terrible, Second Wave coffee just means an emphasis on the cafe itself rather than the specifics of coffee. To close, Coffee Connection is a non-profit cafe that provides an inspiration space for people to chase their dreams starting with a sustainable cup of coffee.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Roots</title><link href="/roots" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Roots" /><published>2020-01-26T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-26T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/roots</id><content type="html" xml:base="/roots">&lt;p&gt;Tucked away in a neighborhood in Culver City, &lt;strong&gt;Bar Nine&lt;/strong&gt; roasts, brews, and serves &lt;em&gt;Third Wave&lt;/em&gt; coffee. Blink once, you would have seen a warehouse. Blink twice, you would have completely missed it. Walls of brick and mortar, a large glass door, and a generic chain-link fence is the only indication that you are remotely in the right place. As the saying goes, “if you know, you know”.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/bar-nine-interior.jpg){:class=&quot;img&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Wait, wait, wait. Let’s take a step back. What is &lt;em&gt;Third Wave&lt;/em&gt; coffee? And what happened to waves one and two??? Quick history lesson, in the mid 1800s, coffee became a commercialized commodity: think Folgers, Maxwell Coffee House, instant coffee. &lt;em&gt;First Wave&lt;/em&gt; coffee in many ways sacrificed quality and taste for mass-produced and affordable coffee. Simply put, it tasted like shit. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Moving into the 1970s, companies like Peet’s and Starbucks looked to provide better quality coffee at a higher premium: think back to those 5 dollar, sugary latte days of your youth. While there was some emphasis on coffee origin, &lt;em&gt;Second Wave&lt;/em&gt; coffee primarily focused on mass-sourcing better beans and unsubstantial, specialty drinks. If &lt;em&gt;First Wave&lt;/em&gt; coffee was a pig, &lt;em&gt;Second Wave&lt;/em&gt; coffee is like slapping lipstick on a cute baby pig called Stacy.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finally, we arrive at &lt;em&gt;Third Wave&lt;/em&gt; coffee. Many people define &lt;em&gt;Third Wave&lt;/em&gt; coffee as the proliferation of specialty coffee, but I would go as far as say &lt;em&gt;Third Wave&lt;/em&gt; coffee is a love for the quality of the entire supply chain that results in a cup of coffee: think of terms like Single Origin, pour-over, complexity, direct trade. In many ways, &lt;em&gt;Third Wave&lt;/em&gt; coffee is an experience revolved solely on the customer’s appreciation for good coffee. You can think of it like wine: massive care and appreciation towards sourcing, storytelling, and quality of the product.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/bar-nine-coffee.jpg){:class=&quot;img&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Alright, now back to &lt;strong&gt;Bar Nine&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Bar Nine&lt;/strong&gt; is textbook, LA, &lt;em&gt;Third Wave&lt;/em&gt; cafe. In many ways, it is a dichotomy of understated design and deeply impassioned coffee, a refreshing alternative from beautiful cafes with subpar coffee. Jack, their in-house roaster, roasts fresh beans every Monday starting from 7 a.m. and has amazing insight into the source and story of their beans. In fact, Jack told me that they actually work directly with international suppliers to source their beans to ensure the very best for us, their customers. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
With in-house roasting, friendly and knowledgable staff, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; great coffee, &lt;strong&gt;Bar Nine&lt;/strong&gt; is by far one of my favorite places to go to simply just enjoy a cup of good coffee. As an environmentally conscious organization, &lt;strong&gt;Bar Nine&lt;/strong&gt; strives to reduce waste caused by the consumption this magical bean water: ranging from a glass takeaway program (instead of paper cups, they give you glass bottles to go *&lt;em&gt;which you can bring back for a discount&lt;/em&gt;*) to natural lighting, solar power to recycled napkins. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you want to dip your toy into the deep, deep world of coffee, &lt;strong&gt;Bar Nine&lt;/strong&gt; is an amazing place to start your &lt;em&gt;Third Wave&lt;/em&gt; journey. Ultimately, if you are paying a high premium for your coffee, not only does the coffee have to be amazing, but you must also experience and feel the passion baristas have towards their craft. &lt;strong&gt;Bar Nine&lt;/strong&gt; is rooted in transparency between the staff’s knowledge and love for coffee and a customer’s needs. If I were to pick a place to completely immerse myself in specialty coffee, &lt;strong&gt;Bar Nine&lt;/strong&gt; would be the place I would begin growing my roots.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Pan</name></author><category term="places" /><summary type="html">Tucked away in a neighborhood in Culver City, Bar Nine roasts, brews, and serves Third Wave coffee. Blink once, you would have seen a warehouse. Blink twice, you would have completely missed it. Walls of brick and mortar, a large glass door, and a generic chain-link fence is the only indication that you are remotely in the right place. As the saying goes, “if you know, you know”. Wait, wait, wait. Let’s take a step back. What is Third Wave coffee? And what happened to waves one and two??? Quick history lesson, in the mid 1800s, coffee became a commercialized commodity: think Folgers, Maxwell Coffee House, instant coffee. First Wave coffee in many ways sacrificed quality and taste for mass-produced and affordable coffee. Simply put, it tasted like shit. Moving into the 1970s, companies like Peet’s and Starbucks looked to provide better quality coffee at a higher premium: think back to those 5 dollar, sugary latte days of your youth. While there was some emphasis on coffee origin, Second Wave coffee primarily focused on mass-sourcing better beans and unsubstantial, specialty drinks. If First Wave coffee was a pig, Second Wave coffee is like slapping lipstick on a cute baby pig called Stacy. Finally, we arrive at Third Wave coffee. Many people define Third Wave coffee as the proliferation of specialty coffee, but I would go as far as say Third Wave coffee is a love for the quality of the entire supply chain that results in a cup of coffee: think of terms like Single Origin, pour-over, complexity, direct trade. In many ways, Third Wave coffee is an experience revolved solely on the customer’s appreciation for good coffee. You can think of it like wine: massive care and appreciation towards sourcing, storytelling, and quality of the product. Alright, now back to Bar Nine. Bar Nine is textbook, LA, Third Wave cafe. In many ways, it is a dichotomy of understated design and deeply impassioned coffee, a refreshing alternative from beautiful cafes with subpar coffee. Jack, their in-house roaster, roasts fresh beans every Monday starting from 7 a.m. and has amazing insight into the source and story of their beans. In fact, Jack told me that they actually work directly with international suppliers to source their beans to ensure the very best for us, their customers. With in-house roasting, friendly and knowledgable staff, and great coffee, Bar Nine is by far one of my favorite places to go to simply just enjoy a cup of good coffee. As an environmentally conscious organization, Bar Nine strives to reduce waste caused by the consumption this magical bean water: ranging from a glass takeaway program (instead of paper cups, they give you glass bottles to go *which you can bring back for a discount*) to natural lighting, solar power to recycled napkins. If you want to dip your toy into the deep, deep world of coffee, Bar Nine is an amazing place to start your Third Wave journey. Ultimately, if you are paying a high premium for your coffee, not only does the coffee have to be amazing, but you must also experience and feel the passion baristas have towards their craft. Bar Nine is rooted in transparency between the staff’s knowledge and love for coffee and a customer’s needs. If I were to pick a place to completely immerse myself in specialty coffee, Bar Nine would be the place I would begin growing my roots.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Home</title><link href="/home" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Home" /><published>2020-01-19T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-19T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/home</id><content type="html" xml:base="/home">&lt;p&gt;In a city, like Los Angeles, I find it all too easy to become consumed by the cacophony of hustle and bustle. The grind, the dream-chasing, the veganism, it’s truly exhausting. Stuck in traffic on the 405, I sometimes wonder how a city could possibly have survived so long without public transportation. With a plethora of hole-in-the-wall cafes to find, it’s hard to choose where to begin. But after a bit of introspection, and maybe a coffee or two, I guess the best place to start is close to home.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Amidst the ruckus of LA, I believe everyone should have a place where they can call home. The world is just too big and too scary to go about it alone. Whether it be your apartment, a cafe, a group of friends, “home” is a place where you can truly be yourself. Just a couple of blocks from UCLA is a coffee shop called &lt;strong&gt;Upside Down&lt;/strong&gt;. Home to the beginning of my coffee obsession, a creative space, and amazingly kind baristas, &lt;strong&gt;Upside Down&lt;/strong&gt; has a special place in my heart.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/upside-down-interior.jpg){:class=&quot;img&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As the name suggests, &lt;strong&gt;Upside Down&lt;/strong&gt; is all about creativity, paradoxically new perspectives, and fun. Run by Jews for Jesus, they believe in creating a space to connect with friends and meet new ones through the medium of coffee, art, and community. They genuinely care about the community they serve and dedicate themselves to the good of the neighborhood. I love &lt;strong&gt;Upside Down&lt;/strong&gt;. Whenever I’m seeking a boost of productivity or creativity, this is my go-to spot to ground myself.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The baristas here are absolutely amazing. While they are incredibly kind and don’t take themselves too seriously, they are super passionate about their coffee. Partnered with &lt;a href=&quot;https://goldenstatecoffee.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Golden State Roasters&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Upside Down&lt;/strong&gt; always has a fresh, single-origin Ethiopian on hand to make that amazing bright and medium-bodied coffee. While they have some pretty cool signature and classic drinks (try their Espresso Tonic), my go-to order is always always a pourover. Consistently, they make some of the best pourovers I have ever tried. If you are looking for something a little off the beaten path, like a hint of something new, I would highly recommend trying their pourovers, black.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/latte-pourover.jpg){:class=&quot;img&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Cool fact: &lt;strong&gt;Upside Down&lt;/strong&gt; is a donation-based coffee shop! So theoretically, you could come here and donate a dollar for an amazing coffee. But after meeting the baristas and feeling the energy that permeates the space, you’ll quickly find out why so many people come here for more than just a cup of coffee. Maybe it’s the ambiance or the people or the coffee, but there is just something about this place that makes me always come back. In the same way that you are nostalgic about your hometown, &lt;strong&gt;Upside Down&lt;/strong&gt; is a place where you can always go back to, a place to call home.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Pan</name></author><category term="places" /><summary type="html">In a city, like Los Angeles, I find it all too easy to become consumed by the cacophony of hustle and bustle. The grind, the dream-chasing, the veganism, it’s truly exhausting. Stuck in traffic on the 405, I sometimes wonder how a city could possibly have survived so long without public transportation. With a plethora of hole-in-the-wall cafes to find, it’s hard to choose where to begin. But after a bit of introspection, and maybe a coffee or two, I guess the best place to start is close to home. Amidst the ruckus of LA, I believe everyone should have a place where they can call home. The world is just too big and too scary to go about it alone. Whether it be your apartment, a cafe, a group of friends, “home” is a place where you can truly be yourself. Just a couple of blocks from UCLA is a coffee shop called Upside Down. Home to the beginning of my coffee obsession, a creative space, and amazingly kind baristas, Upside Down has a special place in my heart. As the name suggests, Upside Down is all about creativity, paradoxically new perspectives, and fun. Run by Jews for Jesus, they believe in creating a space to connect with friends and meet new ones through the medium of coffee, art, and community. They genuinely care about the community they serve and dedicate themselves to the good of the neighborhood. I love Upside Down. Whenever I’m seeking a boost of productivity or creativity, this is my go-to spot to ground myself. The baristas here are absolutely amazing. While they are incredibly kind and don’t take themselves too seriously, they are super passionate about their coffee. Partnered with Golden State Roasters, Upside Down always has a fresh, single-origin Ethiopian on hand to make that amazing bright and medium-bodied coffee. While they have some pretty cool signature and classic drinks (try their Espresso Tonic), my go-to order is always always a pourover. Consistently, they make some of the best pourovers I have ever tried. If you are looking for something a little off the beaten path, like a hint of something new, I would highly recommend trying their pourovers, black. Cool fact: Upside Down is a donation-based coffee shop! So theoretically, you could come here and donate a dollar for an amazing coffee. But after meeting the baristas and feeling the energy that permeates the space, you’ll quickly find out why so many people come here for more than just a cup of coffee. Maybe it’s the ambiance or the people or the coffee, but there is just something about this place that makes me always come back. In the same way that you are nostalgic about your hometown, Upside Down is a place where you can always go back to, a place to call home.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beginnings</title><link href="/beginnings" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginnings" /><published>2020-01-12T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-12T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/beginnings</id><content type="html" xml:base="/beginnings">&lt;p&gt;Hello, world! My name is &lt;strong&gt;Bryan Pan&lt;/strong&gt; and I really love coffee (like, &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt;). As a Computer Science major, I spend the majority of my days with my buttocks screwed into a seat and my eyeballs glued to a screen. I don’t know about you, but, sometimes, I like to imagine a world where my life is completely different. Call me a dreamer but I find solace in fantasizing a life in servitude to something personal, something unconventional. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In many ways, this blog is a big excuse for me to explore and justify my coffee obsession. In many ways, this blog is an escape from the incessant grind of college. But at its core, this blog is a manifestation of my obsessive passion; a creative medium to showcase the real me. While it will most definitely evolve over time, &lt;strong&gt;THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY&lt;/strong&gt; will always be a breeding ground of my tender thoughts, absurd assumptions, and maybe, just maybe, some deep revelations. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As the name suggests, we will be exploring coffee, but more specifically the coffee shops and cafes that act as the foundation for the amazing city that is Los Angeles. From gazillionaires zooming by in their Lamborghinis to everyday Joes hustling towards their dreams, LA is a massive stew of the best parts and also the worst parts of a metropolis. It certainly feels like everyone here is chasing some dream of theirs and I would bet that the majority of them start off every day with a cup of coffee. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are so many aspects of coffee that intrigue me. Unlike most, I don’t drink coffee out of necessity. I drink coffee because I love it. I love the feel of a velvety body from a mediumly roasted Colombian. I love the way the silky aroma of freshly ground coffee laces my clothes. I love the taste of immediate gratification as the raw complexity of a &lt;em&gt;Geisha&lt;/em&gt; varietal flushes my taste buds. I know I sound dramatic, if not magniloquent, but humor me for a bit. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To be completely transparent, &lt;strong&gt;THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY&lt;/strong&gt; was born out of an adherence to my values. I believe that every single person is entitled to find something that they love or love something that they find. While this blog is a symbol of my personal values, I hope that you find the content stimulating yet digestible. &lt;strong&gt;THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY&lt;/strong&gt; will be an adventure for us to undertake together and I’m excited to see where this journey leads us. Please feel free to reach out to me with any feedback, thoughts, responses, emojis, or whatever at &lt;a class=&quot;u-email&quot; href=&quot;mailto:bryanpan342@gmail.com&quot;&gt;bryanpan342@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or on &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/bryanthesnob&quot; class=&quot;username&quot;&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Pan</name></author><category term="tea" /><summary type="html">Hello, world! My name is Bryan Pan and I really love coffee (like, really). As a Computer Science major, I spend the majority of my days with my buttocks screwed into a seat and my eyeballs glued to a screen. I don’t know about you, but, sometimes, I like to imagine a world where my life is completely different. Call me a dreamer but I find solace in fantasizing a life in servitude to something personal, something unconventional. In many ways, this blog is a big excuse for me to explore and justify my coffee obsession. In many ways, this blog is an escape from the incessant grind of college. But at its core, this blog is a manifestation of my obsessive passion; a creative medium to showcase the real me. While it will most definitely evolve over time, THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY will always be a breeding ground of my tender thoughts, absurd assumptions, and maybe, just maybe, some deep revelations. As the name suggests, we will be exploring coffee, but more specifically the coffee shops and cafes that act as the foundation for the amazing city that is Los Angeles. From gazillionaires zooming by in their Lamborghinis to everyday Joes hustling towards their dreams, LA is a massive stew of the best parts and also the worst parts of a metropolis. It certainly feels like everyone here is chasing some dream of theirs and I would bet that the majority of them start off every day with a cup of coffee. There are so many aspects of coffee that intrigue me. Unlike most, I don’t drink coffee out of necessity. I drink coffee because I love it. I love the feel of a velvety body from a mediumly roasted Colombian. I love the way the silky aroma of freshly ground coffee laces my clothes. I love the taste of immediate gratification as the raw complexity of a Geisha varietal flushes my taste buds. I know I sound dramatic, if not magniloquent, but humor me for a bit. To be completely transparent, THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY was born out of an adherence to my values. I believe that every single person is entitled to find something that they love or love something that they find. While this blog is a symbol of my personal values, I hope that you find the content stimulating yet digestible. THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY will be an adventure for us to undertake together and I’m excited to see where this journey leads us. Please feel free to reach out to me with any feedback, thoughts, responses, emojis, or whatever at bryanpan342@gmail.com or on social media!</summary></entry></feed>