<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/tea/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-04-14T19:37:13+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/tea/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">The Grounds of the City | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>A student's journey with coffee</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Onward &amp;amp; Upward</title>
      <link href="/onward_and_upward" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Onward &amp; Upward" />
      <published>2020-04-01T11:59:59+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-01T11:59:59+00:00</updated>
      <id>/onward_and_upward</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/onward_and_upward">&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I have been putting this off for a while now. It has almost been a month since I have last posted on this blog. When I look back at the content I created before, I give a wry smile towards my oblivity (yes I made this word up because it sounds cooler than obliviousness) at the greater situation at large. COVID-19 has undoubtedly affected us all but, while it may seem terrible at first, I have faith that COVID-19 will spark great change in society that is beneficial to all of us.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Personally, I now look back at all the things I have taken for granted with newfound appreciation. This once-in-a-century disease that is rampaging across the world has made me really assess the little things in life. Anywhere from making coffee for my friends to walking into a new coffee shop, I truly miss the little things about this hobby of mine. Of course, I am grateful for so much more that is unrelated to coffee, but then again this is a blog about coffee.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I really hope that the people I have met throughout my coffee adventure are doing well. I know that these times are hard for everyone, but especially small businesses, so wishing them all the best. It truly is the people that you meet in your journey who define your story. There have been wonderful baristas and random people that I have met at coffee shops that defined my love for coffee. And it’s sadly poetic how only in times like these do we stop to think about how important those people are in our development.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In an age of social distancing, I will no longer have the luxury of walking into a new coffee shop and posit opinions of taste. Instead, I want to talk about the under-the-rug, nerdy stuff that really gets my blood pumping when it comes to coffee. Anywhere from ‘how to make coffee’, ‘how can I start making great coffee’, or ‘why do we even use water as our solute’ are all questions I want to talk about and hopefully spark interest in someone else to begin their own coffee addiction.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bryan Pan</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="tea" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Honestly, I have been putting this off for a while now. It has almost been a month since I have last posted on this blog. When I look back at the content I created before, I give a wry smile towards my oblivity (yes I made this word up because it sounds cooler than obliviousness) at the greater situation at large. COVID-19 has undoubtedly affected us all but, while it may seem terrible at first, I have faith that COVID-19 will spark great change in society that is beneficial to all of us. Personally, I now look back at all the things I have taken for granted with newfound appreciation. This once-in-a-century disease that is rampaging across the world has made me really assess the little things in life. Anywhere from making coffee for my friends to walking into a new coffee shop, I truly miss the little things about this hobby of mine. Of course, I am grateful for so much more that is unrelated to coffee, but then again this is a blog about coffee. I really hope that the people I have met throughout my coffee adventure are doing well. I know that these times are hard for everyone, but especially small businesses, so wishing them all the best. It truly is the people that you meet in your journey who define your story. There have been wonderful baristas and random people that I have met at coffee shops that defined my love for coffee. And it’s sadly poetic how only in times like these do we stop to think about how important those people are in our development. In an age of social distancing, I will no longer have the luxury of walking into a new coffee shop and posit opinions of taste. Instead, I want to talk about the under-the-rug, nerdy stuff that really gets my blood pumping when it comes to coffee. Anywhere from ‘how to make coffee’, ‘how can I start making great coffee’, or ‘why do we even use water as our solute’ are all questions I want to talk about and hopefully spark interest in someone else to begin their own coffee addiction.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Liquid Thought</title>
      <link href="/liquid-thought" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Liquid Thought" />
      <published>2020-03-08T09:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-03-08T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/liquid-thought</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/liquid-thought">&lt;p&gt;The sun is rising right now. The sky is a full light blue with rays of light peeking through tall trees and buildings. I’m sipping my coffee. It’s a little over-extracted, but that’s okay. It’s way too early to be writing about coffee. To be completely transparent, I didn’t go to a coffee shop this week. It’s not because I didn’t have the time, I just didn’t feel like going to one. For this post, I want to expose my mind and pour my thoughts onto writing. I want my liquid thoughts to solidify in prose. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have no idea why I didn’t feel like going to a coffee shop this week. It’s not that I didn’t have time and I certainly didn’t run out of places to go. Maybe like an over-extracted coffee, I just exposed myself too much, too quickly, for far too long. To clarify, I’m not sick of coffee. I’m definitely far from it. Honestly, it’s kind of crazy to think that it’s been 10 weeks in the making for this little blog of mine. There have definitely been some posts that are far superior than others in my eyes, but &lt;strong&gt;The Grounds of the City&lt;/strong&gt; was always meant to simply be a breeding ground for my tender thoughts.
&lt;!-- &lt;br/&gt;  
![image](/assets/images/gumption.jpg){:class=&quot;imglit&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Honestly, it baffles me that I’m doing this. I’m chuckling thinking about the absurdity of this blog and how far my passion for coffee has brought me. I originally came into &lt;strong&gt;The Grounds of the City&lt;/strong&gt; with no expecations on how it would look or any bearings on the type of content. I dived in thinking that I would simply “figure it out” as I went along. I honestly don’t know, and don’t care, if anyone reads these posts besides myself. This little blog of mine has essentially become a diary of anything from my absurd assumptions to snobbish takes on bean water. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As my 9th post, this very post marks 10 weeks since I started this project. I never really thought about where I wanted this to go. But looking back at where it all started, I’m quite happy to see how &lt;strong&gt;The Grounds of the City&lt;/strong&gt; has evolved over time. Of course, there is so much that I wish I could change about the blog (I mean let’s be honest, it looks like shit right now). I really hope to continue this hobby of mine beyond this quarter at school. Again, no expectations moving forward, and extremely excited to see where the future takes me.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bryan Pan</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="tea" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">The sun is rising right now. The sky is a full light blue with rays of light peeking through tall trees and buildings. I’m sipping my coffee. It’s a little over-extracted, but that’s okay. It’s way too early to be writing about coffee. To be completely transparent, I didn’t go to a coffee shop this week. It’s not because I didn’t have the time, I just didn’t feel like going to one. For this post, I want to expose my mind and pour my thoughts onto writing. I want my liquid thoughts to solidify in prose. I have no idea why I didn’t feel like going to a coffee shop this week. It’s not that I didn’t have time and I certainly didn’t run out of places to go. Maybe like an over-extracted coffee, I just exposed myself too much, too quickly, for far too long. To clarify, I’m not sick of coffee. I’m definitely far from it. Honestly, it’s kind of crazy to think that it’s been 10 weeks in the making for this little blog of mine. There have definitely been some posts that are far superior than others in my eyes, but The Grounds of the City was always meant to simply be a breeding ground for my tender thoughts. Honestly, it baffles me that I’m doing this. I’m chuckling thinking about the absurdity of this blog and how far my passion for coffee has brought me. I originally came into The Grounds of the City with no expecations on how it would look or any bearings on the type of content. I dived in thinking that I would simply “figure it out” as I went along. I honestly don’t know, and don’t care, if anyone reads these posts besides myself. This little blog of mine has essentially become a diary of anything from my absurd assumptions to snobbish takes on bean water. As my 9th post, this very post marks 10 weeks since I started this project. I never really thought about where I wanted this to go. But looking back at where it all started, I’m quite happy to see how The Grounds of the City has evolved over time. Of course, there is so much that I wish I could change about the blog (I mean let’s be honest, it looks like shit right now). I really hope to continue this hobby of mine beyond this quarter at school. Again, no expectations moving forward, and extremely excited to see where the future takes me.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Beginnings</title>
      <link href="/beginnings" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginnings" />
      <published>2020-01-12T09:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-01-12T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/beginnings</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/beginnings">&lt;p&gt;Hello, world! My name is &lt;strong&gt;Bryan Pan&lt;/strong&gt; and I really love coffee (like, &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt;). As a Computer Science major, I spend the majority of my days with my buttocks screwed into a seat and my eyeballs glued to a screen. I don’t know about you, but, sometimes, I like to imagine a world where my life is completely different. Call me a dreamer but I find solace in fantasizing a life in servitude to something personal, something unconventional. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In many ways, this blog is a big excuse for me to explore and justify my coffee obsession. In many ways, this blog is an escape from the incessant grind of college. But at its core, this blog is a manifestation of my obsessive passion; a creative medium to showcase the real me. While it will most definitely evolve over time, &lt;strong&gt;THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY&lt;/strong&gt; will always be a breeding ground of my tender thoughts, absurd assumptions, and maybe, just maybe, some deep revelations. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As the name suggests, we will be exploring coffee, but more specifically the coffee shops and cafes that act as the foundation for the amazing city that is Los Angeles. From gazillionaires zooming by in their Lamborghinis to everyday Joes hustling towards their dreams, LA is a massive stew of the best parts and also the worst parts of a metropolis. It certainly feels like everyone here is chasing some dream of theirs and I would bet that the majority of them start off every day with a cup of coffee. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are so many aspects of coffee that intrigue me. Unlike most, I don’t drink coffee out of necessity. I drink coffee because I love it. I love the feel of a velvety body from a mediumly roasted Colombian. I love the way the silky aroma of freshly ground coffee laces my clothes. I love the taste of immediate gratification as the raw complexity of a &lt;em&gt;Geisha&lt;/em&gt; varietal flushes my taste buds. I know I sound dramatic, if not magniloquent, but humor me for a bit. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To be completely transparent, &lt;strong&gt;THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY&lt;/strong&gt; was born out of an adherence to my values. I believe that every single person is entitled to find something that they love or love something that they find. While this blog is a symbol of my personal values, I hope that you find the content stimulating yet digestible. &lt;strong&gt;THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY&lt;/strong&gt; will be an adventure for us to undertake together and I’m excited to see where this journey leads us. Please feel free to reach out to me with any feedback, thoughts, responses, emojis, or whatever at &lt;a class=&quot;u-email&quot; href=&quot;mailto:bryanpan342@gmail.com&quot;&gt;bryanpan342@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or on &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/bryanthesnob&quot; class=&quot;username&quot;&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bryan Pan</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="tea" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Hello, world! My name is Bryan Pan and I really love coffee (like, really). As a Computer Science major, I spend the majority of my days with my buttocks screwed into a seat and my eyeballs glued to a screen. I don’t know about you, but, sometimes, I like to imagine a world where my life is completely different. Call me a dreamer but I find solace in fantasizing a life in servitude to something personal, something unconventional. In many ways, this blog is a big excuse for me to explore and justify my coffee obsession. In many ways, this blog is an escape from the incessant grind of college. But at its core, this blog is a manifestation of my obsessive passion; a creative medium to showcase the real me. While it will most definitely evolve over time, THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY will always be a breeding ground of my tender thoughts, absurd assumptions, and maybe, just maybe, some deep revelations. As the name suggests, we will be exploring coffee, but more specifically the coffee shops and cafes that act as the foundation for the amazing city that is Los Angeles. From gazillionaires zooming by in their Lamborghinis to everyday Joes hustling towards their dreams, LA is a massive stew of the best parts and also the worst parts of a metropolis. It certainly feels like everyone here is chasing some dream of theirs and I would bet that the majority of them start off every day with a cup of coffee. There are so many aspects of coffee that intrigue me. Unlike most, I don’t drink coffee out of necessity. I drink coffee because I love it. I love the feel of a velvety body from a mediumly roasted Colombian. I love the way the silky aroma of freshly ground coffee laces my clothes. I love the taste of immediate gratification as the raw complexity of a Geisha varietal flushes my taste buds. I know I sound dramatic, if not magniloquent, but humor me for a bit. To be completely transparent, THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY was born out of an adherence to my values. I believe that every single person is entitled to find something that they love or love something that they find. While this blog is a symbol of my personal values, I hope that you find the content stimulating yet digestible. THE GROUNDS OF THE CITY will be an adventure for us to undertake together and I’m excited to see where this journey leads us. Please feel free to reach out to me with any feedback, thoughts, responses, emojis, or whatever at bryanpan342@gmail.com or on social media!</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
